<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Writing on Jillian Ada Burrows</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/</link><description>Recent content in Writing on Jillian Ada Burrows</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><atom:link href="http://adaburrows.com/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Original Name for Mt. Olympus</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2021-04-07-olympic-mountains/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2021-04-07-olympic-mountains/</guid><description>It&amp;rsquo;s not Sun-a-do, even though many people still think that.</description></item><item><title>What is value and how should we value things?</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2020-12-08-what-is-value/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2020-12-08-what-is-value/</guid><description>Can we tease apart the relationship between money, value, and the underlying physics around what we do? Can we create a precise physical definition to measure value like we have established for the measure of Volts and Amps? Or will money and economics be forever past the realm of hard physics and engineering because the relationships are not defined precisely or consistently enough? Do we even understand what it is that money does well enough to have that discussion?</description></item><item><title>Music to Study for #BLM</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2020-08-25-music-blm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2020-08-25-music-blm/</guid><description>We&amp;rsquo;ve sat to down to meditate on possible differences between what we think people need and and their actual needs. Again, come join me. Gather round, let us listen. If it helps, you can go through the stretches in the previous blog post. This is going to be the first in a series of articles that might stretch some of you beyond your comfort zone. If you happen to be a person of color, this is likely to bring up trauma.</description></item><item><title>Come, Let's Build a World Together</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2020-6-28-come-lets-gather/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2020-6-28-come-lets-gather/</guid><description>Please, sit down with me. Gather round and form a circle. If there are too many people, form another circular row behind the first. Leave yourself some space to be comfortable. Get cozy. Yes. You are reading and this is just a gathering in our respective minds. Feel free to include as many or as few people in this gathering as you would like.
Center # If you&amp;rsquo;re comfortable with it, please close your eyes while we do a little settling in.</description></item><item><title>Star Trek or US Space Force?</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2020-05-19-star-trek-or-us-space-force/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2020-05-19-star-trek-or-us-space-force/</guid><description>Since this administration unfurled the new official emblem for the Space Force. Many people, including actors from Star Trek, have raised issues with how similar it looks to the Starfleet Command logo. It turns out it’s no accident that this has happened, but not for the reasons you probably think. When Star Trek came on the air in the 60s, there was already a long legacy of the Air Force using similar logos and seals going back to at least 1935. Star Trek has borrowed from real life on numerous occasions, from riffing off the UN for the United Federation of planets in Star Trek The Motion Picture from 1979 to the mirror universe Terran Empire emblem.</description></item><item><title>Coronavirus SARS-CoV-2: Dissecting the virus</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2020-04-10-coronavirus-sars-cov2-dissecting-the-virus/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2020-04-10-coronavirus-sars-cov2-dissecting-the-virus/</guid><description>An updated scientific and clinical overview.</description></item><item><title>Coronavirus SARS-CoV2: 03/17/2020</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2020-03-17-coronavirus-sars-cov2/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2020-03-17-coronavirus-sars-cov2/</guid><description>COVID-19 symptoms can be distinguished from flu symptoms by one main factor: It does not cause a runny nose. That being said, one can still have a runny nose if one is infected with multiple viruses (Wu et al.). The other give away is developing a dry cough. The other symptoms in order of severity are: Fever, Dry Cough, Fatigue, Sputum production (that’s thick mucus in the lungs), Shortness of breath, Muscle pain/joint pain, Sore Throat, Headache, Chills. Less common symptoms are: Nausea/vomiting, Nasal congestion, Diarrhea. Symptoms typically start with fever then progress to a dry cough.</description></item><item><title>Our Broken Realities</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2020-02-10-our-broken-realities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2020-02-10-our-broken-realities/</guid><description>Can we mend our splintered reality?</description></item><item><title>A History of Amazon Deforestation</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-11-14-a-history-of-amazon-deforestation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-11-14-a-history-of-amazon-deforestation/</guid><description>The problem with Brazil doing any settler-colonizer style agriculture is they have just the smallest bit of suitable land. They have just the smallest bit of natural prairie at the south side of the country. It’s only in the State of Rio Grande do Sol. That same prairie bioregion extends down into Uruguay and Buenos Aires, but it’s absolutely tiny in Brazil (Overbeck et al., 2008). So what’s Brazil to do? The grileiros (from grilos, locusts) come to plague the land. They tear down existing biospheres. They steal land and kill Indigenous people. (Butler, 2011), (Arsenault &amp;amp; Mendes, 2017), (Zaitchik, 2019)</description></item><item><title>Root Beer’s Indigenous Roots</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-07-21-root-beers-indigneous-roots/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-07-21-root-beers-indigneous-roots/</guid><description>Root beer is now a ubiquitous soft drink in America, but it’s modern form is nothing like the original teas brewed by Indigenous peoples on the American continent. It’s loaded with sugar. It’s made with artificial flavoring. It’s much less of a medicine than it originally was made to be.</description></item><item><title>The Origin of Concentration Camps</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-07-31-the-origin-of-concentration-camps/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-07-31-the-origin-of-concentration-camps/</guid><description>Concentration camps or internment camps are any mass imprisonment of people without charges, typically of citizens of an enemy or anyone suspected of terrorism. Often times, these camps are not called concentration camps or interment camps, as the intention at first may vary. No matter the original intent, concentration camps or interment camps always seem to evolve into situations where death reigns.</description></item><item><title>Help! I’m Being Stalked by Robots!</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-03-05-help-im-being-stalked-by-robots/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-03-05-help-im-being-stalked-by-robots/</guid><description>Facebook and Twitter already know every link you click on and everything you’ve liked and every person you’ve even interacted with on their platform. However, their reach doesn’t stop there. Every time you visit a web page which uses an advertising platform as a partner (which might include Twitter, Facebook, or a number of others), those companies are informed of exactly which pages you visited on the Internet. They know which blogs you frequent, what news articles you read, and the items you might have considered buying. They may even know what sex toys you’ve been thinking of buying from the supposed comfort and privacy of your own bed.</description></item><item><title>Martin Luther King Jr. Stares Towards the 16th Street Baptist Church</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-01-22-mlkj-stares-towards-the-16th-street-baptist-church/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-01-22-mlkj-stares-towards-the-16th-street-baptist-church/</guid><description>I met MLKJ’s statue in Birmingham, AL. He’s on a platform, standing tall and regal. He’s looking across the way past the statues of the four little girls frozen in time, where they likely used to play on the street corner, towards the church where those four girls were killed by a group of racists who planted a bomb intended for organizers at the church.</description></item><item><title>The Plundering of Nations, Elder Nathan Phillips, the MAGA Boys, and MMIW</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-01-20-the-plundering-of-nations-elder-nathan-phillips-maga-boys-mmiw/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-01-20-the-plundering-of-nations-elder-nathan-phillips-maga-boys-mmiw/</guid><description>The conflict between elder Nathan Phillips and the #MAGA kids is more than racism. The kids who were harassing the Omaha Nation elder may have been racist, but it’s still about the plundering of nations. Women and children disappear from reservation territory daily. The current laws make #MMIW cases likely fall under federal jurisdiction, but with additional complications and holes.</description></item><item><title>The Perpetual Nomad</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-08-15-the-peretual-nomad/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-08-15-the-peretual-nomad/</guid><description>I seem bound to wander the earth. I seem to be called to many places to either observe and communicate, to pray, or to help in the most appropriate way. I suppose I am a teacher of sorts, not the kind you’d find in classroom. No, I’m more the kind you might find from a time long ago. I tell stories as the rhizomatic strands of reality become woven into the patterns I see.</description></item><item><title>Baby, You Incomplete Me</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-07-21-baby-you-incomplete-me/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-07-21-baby-you-incomplete-me/</guid><description>A mathematical look at logic versus emotion.</description></item><item><title>150 Years of the 1868 Ft. Laramie Treaty</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-05-04-150-years-of-the-1868-ft-laramie-treaty/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-05-04-150-years-of-the-1868-ft-laramie-treaty/</guid><description>My family’s ties to the fate of the Lakota Nation.</description></item><item><title>The Forests of a Nation</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-03-30-the-forests-of-a-nation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-03-30-the-forests-of-a-nation/</guid><description>How time transformed and carved our forests and the lessons embedded within.</description></item><item><title>Fake Accounts, Bots, and Security Culture</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-03-02-fake-accounts-bots-and-security-culture/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-03-02-fake-accounts-bots-and-security-culture/</guid><description>Accepting a bot’s friend request and going along with “chain letter” advice are terrible ideas.</description></item><item><title>Has War Changed the Way We Do Relationships? A few interesting correlations with industrialization, war, and relationships.</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-01-29-has-war-changed-the-way-we-do-relationships/</link><pubDate>Mon, 29 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-01-29-has-war-changed-the-way-we-do-relationships/</guid><description>Divorce rates have spiked after wars. Divorce/marriage percentage rates have basically increased twofold or so since before WWII. Currently, that ratio is hovering right around 50%. There has been a greater decrease in marriages than divorces starting in 1984.</description></item><item><title>Toccata &amp; Fugue in the Key of Blockchain</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-01-20-toccata-and-fugue-in-the-key-of-blockchain/</link><pubDate>Sat, 20 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-01-20-toccata-and-fugue-in-the-key-of-blockchain/</guid><description>The origins of the underlying data structure has everything to do with ensuring a document or set of documents can be proved published in a particular form at a certain time. In this context, a document could be an image, audio file, movie, or other computer file. This is incredibly general and adaptable to many different circumstances.</description></item><item><title>Does Blockchain Generate Trust?</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-01-16-does-blockchain-generate-trust/</link><pubDate>Tue, 16 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-01-16-does-blockchain-generate-trust/</guid><description>Generating trust from nothing is one of the first major feats blockchain is hyped to do, but blockchain itself doesn’t generate trust out of nothing. It actually derives from the system in which blockchain is used. A blockchain is actually just a chain of blocks of data having a particular structure which ensures its self-integrity, it can only be used to guarantee the data written to the chain was done so in a certain way. Multiple blockchains can be created with the same data up to a certain point — in fact, Bitcoin does this all the time in the mining process and the fork stays around until a majority of nodes choose the fork which grows longest.</description></item><item><title>What Can We Do About Net Neutrality?</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-01-13-what-can-we-do-about-net-neutrality/</link><pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-01-13-what-can-we-do-about-net-neutrality/</guid><description>Only by replacing ISPs with our own providers built to be more open from the ground up, can we bypass their newfound ability to control what travels over their networks.</description></item><item><title>Bitcoin is An Energy Hog -- and its value seems tied to that fact</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2017-12-27-bitcoin-is-an-energy-hog/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2017-12-27-bitcoin-is-an-energy-hog/</guid><description>The price of bitcoin from around 2015 until mid-October 2017, tracks with the price of electricity in China. From August and October, it correlates with the average US cost of energy. In November, it goes on a space walk to a new energy level. By the start of December, it moves with the average cost of electricity in NYC.</description></item><item><title>Insincerely Yours — The GOP &amp; FCC</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2017-12-22-insincerely-yours-the-gop-fcc/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2017-12-22-insincerely-yours-the-gop-fcc/</guid><description>All the Anti-Net Neutrality Propaganda Fit to Print</description></item><item><title>Weaving our Worlds</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2017-12-04-weaving-our-worlds/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Dec 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2017-12-04-weaving-our-worlds/</guid><description>The good thing is that we don’t have to be what we’ve become, what we’ve made ourselves to be. We are more than what we’ve made ourselves to be. We can pray and grow and learn to become more than we’ve made ourselves to be. Let us remember that.</description></item><item><title>The Hypothetical Future of Space Communications</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2017-11-28-the-hypothetical-future-of-space-communications/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2017-11-28-the-hypothetical-future-of-space-communications/</guid><description>Imagine being on Mars, giving a presentation at a conference on Earth with real time audio and video (or VR even). All it might possibly require is a sufficient amount of planning to store separated entangled photon pairs in both locations and proper timing of a signal to initiate the protocol a suitable time before the presentation. This means we’d still experience a delay, but it would only happen before the stream starts — like a sort of quantum buffering. Of course, this is my imagination running wild. Science will still have see if it’s even possible.</description></item><item><title>Towards a portable solar/wind replacement for gas generators</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2017-10-13-renewable-energy-generator-replacement/</link><pubDate>Fri, 13 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2017-10-13-renewable-energy-generator-replacement/</guid><description>This is a general overview of how to design a solar power system, preferably a portable one. This takes a look at the power density disparities between gas powered generators and solar power systems. It also provides an overview of energy requirements for a few common tools, appliances, and home health needs. It then guides the reader through the calculations and decisions needed in order to build a proper solar power system.</description></item><item><title>Have we lost touch with the reality of making ends meet?</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2017-05-24-reality-of-making-ends-meet/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2017-05-24-reality-of-making-ends-meet/</guid><description>I saw a headline float past me recently. I vaguely remember something similar to &amp;ldquo;Can a gig economy survive with minimum wage?&amp;rdquo; It flew past as I flicked my screen in a different direction and all I caught was that question, begging me to answer it. Is a “gig economy” really any different than what we as humans have done in the past? Or is it just a buzz word that we’re tossing around because the employment situation looks grim and there’s technology to help facilitate the process?</description></item><item><title>Understanding Standing Rock</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2016-11-26-understanding-standing-rock/</link><pubDate>Sat, 26 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2016-11-26-understanding-standing-rock/</guid><description>I spent week at the Oceti Sakowin Camp from 11 November 2016 through 18 November 2016. It was far too short of a time. I felt at home there, among the water protectors. The camp technically begins on the reservation with a group known as the Rosebud Camp. Most of it is actually just north of a bridge with signs marking that one is leaving the reservation. It would be easy to just say it is on US Army Corps of Engineers’ land, however in the 1851 Treaty of Fort Laramie the land of the Sioux stretches upward along the Missouri River and all the way along the Heart River, which flows just south of Bismarck and through Mandan. The camp barely touches that vast swath of land.</description></item><item><title>Robert “Bobby” F. Kennedy Jr Speaks at Standing Rock</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2016-11-16-bobby-kennedy-jr-standing-rock/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Nov 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2016-11-16-bobby-kennedy-jr-standing-rock/</guid><description>Yesterday, November 15, 2016, Bobby Kennedy Jr. came to stand with us at the Oceti Sakowin Camp. He gave us encouragement and set a gauntlet for others to follow in his footsteps and support democracy by standing with Standing Rock. Below is the transcript of his speech which I recorded [due to back ground noise, certain parts of it were very hard to make out].</description></item><item><title>Soul Upgrade</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2016-10-09-soul-upgrade/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2016-10-09-soul-upgrade/</guid><description>Today, I woke up. I was slightly more hungover than expected and, somehow, slightly more entangled in the soul of a friend who, just over a week ago, was hit by a car going full speed while trying to flag down help. At first, she was someone who talked to me at the local bar where she worked. Eventually, our relationship grew little by little. Before long we were talking about art, our traumas and struggles in life, and how we wanted the world to change. About a month ago, she told me, “I’m doing it. I’m giving my notice. I’m going to work on art full time. You should come by my studio sometime and we should work on a project together.” Replying excitedly, I said, “That would be awesome! Yes, let’s plan on it.” — which was all I could get in before she hurried off down the bar to serve a new customer, popping by every now and then to exchange a few words. It was becoming obvious our friendship was blossoming beyond what the structure of hanging out at the bar while she worked could hold.</description></item><item><title>What do school shootings tell us about our culture?</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2015-10-03-what-do-school-shootings-tell-us-about-our-culture/</link><pubDate>Sat, 03 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2015-10-03-what-do-school-shootings-tell-us-about-our-culture/</guid><description>We should broaden the context from the strict definition of mental illness to general mental health and coping mechanisms. If examined in the scope of psychology as currently practiced, none of this necessarily falls under the purview of mental illness.</description></item><item><title>How to Make a Time-b, I mean, Timepiece —or— Why People Who Get Scared About Things They Know Nothing About Make Me Want to Cry</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2015-10-02-how-to-make-a-time-peice/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Oct 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2015-10-02-how-to-make-a-time-peice/</guid><description>There’s, of course, the current tale of Ahmed Mohamed and his clock. He’s a 14 year old boy of Sudanese descent who happens to be an American kid and Muslim (why blame a kid for his religion?). His father happens to have run for presidency in Sudan, twice. Should any of that matter in this case? No, but it seems to have mattered. According to CNN, the teacher to whom he showed the clock was the one who felt threatened. Now, it might be arguable it was just the appearance of an eight inch wide metal pencil box with a time readout that caused the worry. I would say that’s an argument made out of ignorance and poor education regarding electronics.</description></item><item><title>Abbreviating Huge and Minuscule Numbers with Math and JavaScript</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2014-11-18-abbreviating-huge-and-miniscule-numbers-with-math-and-javascript/</link><pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2014-11-18-abbreviating-huge-and-miniscule-numbers-with-math-and-javascript/</guid><description>I’m sure there are quite a few ways to do this. What if we could write something with only two non-repeated conditionals using a few math concepts in eight lines of code?</description></item><item><title>What to Look for in PHP 5.4.0</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2011-12-17-what-to-look-for-in-php-5-4-0/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2011-12-17-what-to-look-for-in-php-5-4-0/</guid><description>PHP 5.4.0 will arrive soon. The PHP team is working to bring to some very nice presents to PHP developers. In the previous release of 5.3.0 they had added a few language changes. This version is no different. Some of the other changes include the ability to use DTrace for watching PHP apps in BSD variants (there is a loadable kernel module for Linux folks). This release features many speed and security improvements along with some phasing out of older language features (Y2K compliance is no longer optional). The mysql extensions for ext/mysql, mysqli, and pdo now use the MySql native driver (mysqlnd). This release also improves support for multibyte strings.</description></item><item><title>The State of Functional Programming in PHP 5.3.x</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2011-06-24-the-state-of-functional-programming-in-php-5-3-x/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jun 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2011-06-24-the-state-of-functional-programming-in-php-5-3-x/</guid><description>A few weeks ago, I started looking into the possibility of functional programming in PHP. I stumbled across the capability of defining anonymous functions — starting with PHP 5.3.0. These can be used to define closures with bound variables and also for partial application or currying. Higher order functions can also be defined.</description></item><item><title>Documentation for gRaphael: g.line.js</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2011-02-21-documentation-for-graphael-g-line-js/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2011 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2011-02-21-documentation-for-graphael-g-line-js/</guid><description>gRaphael provides an easy way of creating charts through JavaScript. Unfortunately, many people have complained about how poorly it is documented. In the interest of seeing more good looking charts on websites, I decided to go through the code and post documentation here.</description></item><item><title>Centering Map Viewports Near Locations while Preserving Privacy</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2010-11-09-map-viewport-location-privacy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 09 Nov 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2010-11-09-map-viewport-location-privacy/</guid><description>What geoloqi needs is a method of offsetting the current location which statistically cannot be tricked or munged into reproducing one’s current location. This is the major constraint: How does one ensure that a dedicated (stalker/zombie/attacker/real life spamer/salesman) cannot reproduce one’s location, given the algorithm and a set of data requested from the public API for the map center?</description></item><item><title>Profound Similarities</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2010-01-25-profound-similarities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2010-01-25-profound-similarities/</guid><description>I was messing around with some ideas the other day and noticed some similarities between some very beautiful identities.</description></item><item><title>Duplicating VirtualBox Machines the Hard Way</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2010-01-23-duplicating-virtualbox-machines-the-hard-way/</link><pubDate>Sat, 23 Jan 2010 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2010-01-23-duplicating-virtualbox-machines-the-hard-way/</guid><description>Exactly what it says on the tin. I had yet to learn about the built in method for duplicating images.</description></item><item><title>Interesting Fibonacci Goodness</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2009-12-30-interesting-fibonacci-goodness/</link><pubDate>Wed, 30 Dec 2009 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2009-12-30-interesting-fibonacci-goodness/</guid><description>Last year I was working on deriving a matrix based method for translating and rotating various polygons around pentagons. In the process of this I got sidetracked and started to look into the golden mean. People swoon over how it defines the most beautiful rectangles! It crops up inside pentagons and various 3-D polyhedra. It’s glorious. It’s just like how a circle has the ratio pi, and it has a name too: phi. I’ll be writing it down in Greek from here on out (it’s originally from there anyway). So learn this shape: \varphi Sometimes people write it out like this: \phi Either way it’s just a variable name. Sometimes it refers to something other than the golden mean, but here it’s the golden mean. As I found powers of \varphi , I kept noticing certain values popping up in sequence. It turns out that one can find powers of \varphi through the following formula:</description></item></channel></rss>