<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Culture on Jillian Ada Burrows</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/categories/culture/</link><description>Recent content in Culture on Jillian Ada Burrows</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://adaburrows.com/categories/culture/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>What is value and how should we value things?</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2020-12-08-what-is-value/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2020-12-08-what-is-value/</guid><description>Can we tease apart the relationship between money, value, and the underlying physics around what we do? Can we create a precise physical definition to measure value like we have established for the measure of Volts and Amps? Or will money and economics be forever past the realm of hard physics and engineering because the relationships are not defined precisely or consistently enough? Do we even understand what it is that money does well enough to have that discussion?</description></item><item><title>Star Trek or US Space Force?</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2020-05-19-star-trek-or-us-space-force/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2020-05-19-star-trek-or-us-space-force/</guid><description>Since this administration unfurled the new official emblem for the Space Force. Many people, including actors from Star Trek, have raised issues with how similar it looks to the Starfleet Command logo. It turns out it’s no accident that this has happened, but not for the reasons you probably think. When Star Trek came on the air in the 60s, there was already a long legacy of the Air Force using similar logos and seals going back to at least 1935. Star Trek has borrowed from real life on numerous occasions, from riffing off the UN for the United Federation of planets in Star Trek The Motion Picture from 1979 to the mirror universe Terran Empire emblem.</description></item><item><title>Our Broken Realities</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2020-02-10-our-broken-realities/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2020-02-10-our-broken-realities/</guid><description>Can we mend our splintered reality?</description></item><item><title>Root Beer’s Indigenous Roots</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-07-21-root-beers-indigneous-roots/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-07-21-root-beers-indigneous-roots/</guid><description>Root beer is now a ubiquitous soft drink in America, but it’s modern form is nothing like the original teas brewed by Indigenous peoples on the American continent. It’s loaded with sugar. It’s made with artificial flavoring. It’s much less of a medicine than it originally was made to be.</description></item><item><title>The Origin of Concentration Camps</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-07-31-the-origin-of-concentration-camps/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-07-31-the-origin-of-concentration-camps/</guid><description>Concentration camps or internment camps are any mass imprisonment of people without charges, typically of citizens of an enemy or anyone suspected of terrorism. Often times, these camps are not called concentration camps or interment camps, as the intention at first may vary. No matter the original intent, concentration camps or interment camps always seem to evolve into situations where death reigns.</description></item><item><title>Help! I’m Being Stalked by Robots!</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-03-05-help-im-being-stalked-by-robots/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-03-05-help-im-being-stalked-by-robots/</guid><description>Facebook and Twitter already know every link you click on and everything you’ve liked and every person you’ve even interacted with on their platform. However, their reach doesn’t stop there. Every time you visit a web page which uses an advertising platform as a partner (which might include Twitter, Facebook, or a number of others), those companies are informed of exactly which pages you visited on the Internet. They know which blogs you frequent, what news articles you read, and the items you might have considered buying. They may even know what sex toys you’ve been thinking of buying from the supposed comfort and privacy of your own bed.</description></item><item><title>Martin Luther King Jr. Stares Towards the 16th Street Baptist Church</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-01-22-mlkj-stares-towards-the-16th-street-baptist-church/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-01-22-mlkj-stares-towards-the-16th-street-baptist-church/</guid><description>I met MLKJ’s statue in Birmingham, AL. He’s on a platform, standing tall and regal. He’s looking across the way past the statues of the four little girls frozen in time, where they likely used to play on the street corner, towards the church where those four girls were killed by a group of racists who planted a bomb intended for organizers at the church.</description></item><item><title>The Plundering of Nations, Elder Nathan Phillips, the MAGA Boys, and MMIW</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-01-20-the-plundering-of-nations-elder-nathan-phillips-maga-boys-mmiw/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2019-01-20-the-plundering-of-nations-elder-nathan-phillips-maga-boys-mmiw/</guid><description>The conflict between elder Nathan Phillips and the #MAGA kids is more than racism. The kids who were harassing the Omaha Nation elder may have been racist, but it’s still about the plundering of nations. Women and children disappear from reservation territory daily. The current laws make #MMIW cases likely fall under federal jurisdiction, but with additional complications and holes.</description></item><item><title>The Perpetual Nomad</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-08-15-the-peretual-nomad/</link><pubDate>Wed, 15 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-08-15-the-peretual-nomad/</guid><description>I seem bound to wander the earth. I seem to be called to many places to either observe and communicate, to pray, or to help in the most appropriate way. I suppose I am a teacher of sorts, not the kind you’d find in classroom. No, I’m more the kind you might find from a time long ago. I tell stories as the rhizomatic strands of reality become woven into the patterns I see.</description></item><item><title>Baby, You Incomplete Me</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-07-21-baby-you-incomplete-me/</link><pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-07-21-baby-you-incomplete-me/</guid><description>A mathematical look at logic versus emotion.</description></item><item><title>150 Years of the 1868 Ft. Laramie Treaty</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-05-04-150-years-of-the-1868-ft-laramie-treaty/</link><pubDate>Fri, 04 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-05-04-150-years-of-the-1868-ft-laramie-treaty/</guid><description>My family’s ties to the fate of the Lakota Nation.</description></item><item><title>The Forests of a Nation</title><link>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-03-30-the-forests-of-a-nation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>http://adaburrows.com/writing/2018-03-30-the-forests-of-a-nation/</guid><description>How time transformed and carved our forests and the lessons embedded within.</description></item></channel></rss>